<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-05-08T15:02:47-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">Rachel Edelman</title><subtitle>I'm a public interest designer based in San Francisco. 
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Syracuse Business Portal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/12/BusinessPortal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Syracuse Business Portal" /><published>2016-10-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/12/BusinessPortal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/12/BusinessPortal.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/smallbiz-syr-homepage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Business Portal homepage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can the city of Syracuse, New York best serve local business owners? With a small, but dedicated staff, the city’s Division of Business Development needed an online presence to compliment their in-person services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“To grow our economy we don’t have the ability to talk to every single person with an idea. We felt it was important to make that if you have an idea, you have a place to go to start thinking about it.” - &lt;a href=&quot;http://wrvo.org/post/syracuse-web-portal-one-stop-shop-businesses&quot;&gt;Deputy Commissioner of Business Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We built &lt;a href=&quot;https://business.syrgov.net/&quot;&gt;business.syrgov.net&lt;/a&gt;, a portal where local entrepreneurs can learn about starting a business, find city regulations, check the status of their permits, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the product designer on this team, were I worked alongside a service designer, a product manager, and several engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;process&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/smallbiz-tracker-iterations.png&quot; alt=&quot;Variations on search prompt text.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Microcopy iterations. Every detail of the site was designed with care, and I went through multiple iterations of each aspect of the site.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;accessibility&quot;&gt;Accessibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A government website must serve all residents. I needed to meet users where they were, which includes a diverse range of abilities, devices, languages, and levels of digital literacy. I designed the layout mobile-first, so users would have an excellent experience whether they were on their phone or a desktop computer. I chose system fonts so the content would load quickly, even for users on poor connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;visual-design&quot;&gt;Visual Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The visual identity is designed to be to modern and approachable, yet authoritative. Entrepreneurs should feel welcome on the site, and trust it to give them accurate, up to date information on regulations and requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hierarchy-and-navigation&quot;&gt;Hierarchy and Navigation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our research uncovered that one of the biggest barriers facing new business owners is a lack of knowledge of the landscape. Specifically, they “don’t know what they don’t know”. It was important to give users a clear path to navigate the site, whether or not they knew exactly what they were looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/smallbiz-syr-layout-iterations.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Wireframes iterating on the homepage layout.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We built on Code for America’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeforamerica.org/government-partners/long-beach-ca&quot;&gt;2016 Fellowship in Long Beach&lt;/a&gt;, where they piloted the Plan, Open, Grow model. To this I added several forms of navigation, including bread crumbs and a table of contents for each section. This allows experienced users to jump to the exact topic they’re interested in, while also providing a clear path to new users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;human-touch&quot;&gt;Human Touch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/smallbiz-syr-content.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of an interior page&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Screenshot of an interior page.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our research showed that that users highly value the ability to interact directly with city staff. I broke up long blocks of content with easily clickable contact links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;application-tracker&quot;&gt;Application Tracker&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, business owners needed to call the city to find out the status of their business license and  permit applications. Our application tracker pulls in data from the city’s permitting software, giving applicants access to quick, up to date statuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/smallbiz-tracker-mockups.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of different screens in the application tracker&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My challenge was to present data so that users could easily find the information that was relevant to them. For logistical reason, we needed to let users look up applications with tracking number, without logging into an account. The applications contain many steps and sub-steps. A developer looking for information on why an inspection failed has different needs than a business owner who wants to know when their license expires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I broke the data up into logical sections with clear headings and added icons and colors to help users scan and understand the information at a glance. I designed a summary section at the top with the overall application status and time sensitive information. For one step of the application, we were unable to get live data from the city’s permitting system. To help users understand what was happening in this step, I added a plain language explanation of the process. This compromise keeps users from feeling in dark as they wait for the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="CodeforAmerica" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ReqCheck</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/11/reqcheck.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ReqCheck" /><published>2016-10-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/11/reqcheck</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/11/reqcheck.html">&lt;p&gt;ReqCheck is a lightweight web app that interprets vaccine records. I completed this project while a Design Fellow at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeforamerica.org&quot;&gt;Code for America&lt;/a&gt;, a national nonprofit that makes government services simple, effective, and easy to use. The fellowship is a selective program that pairs teams experienced technologists with cities on a year long project. I worked with the Kansas City, MO Health Department, where my team’s mission was to improve access to childhood immunization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/reqcheck-participatory-design.png&quot; alt=&quot;Making a journey map with the nurses&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Leading a participatory design exercise with front-line Health Department staff.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with research. We identified three major stakeholders: parents, health department employees, and the broader Kansas City health community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/reqcheck-journey-map.png&quot; class=&quot;inline-thumb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/thumbs/reqcheck-map-thumb.png&quot; alt=&quot;KCMO Health Department Childhood Immunization Process chart showing painpoints and bottlenecks.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used a variety of techniques to learn about these groups: stakeholder interviews, shadowing, intercept interviews, and participatory design exercises. I wrote scripts, recruited participants, and conducted interviews. I then synthesized this research to present key insights to team members, funders, and other stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this process, we identified pain points and bottlenecks. We decided to focus on two issues where we knew we could have a significant impact. First, that there was no way to triage families at intake, and second that vaccine records were difficult to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/reqcheck-wireframes.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Early wireframes of the UI.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our solution was ReqCheck: a web app running an algorithm built on top of vaccine requirements from the Centers for Disease Control. The app pulls data from the Health Department’s electronic health records, and determines if a patient is up to date on their vaccines. With our app, registration staff can triage without consulting a nurse, and nurses can make decisions faster and more accurately. This significantly streamlines the clinic’s work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I think it’s clean and organized. It’s not confusing, because everything’s right where it needs to be. It looks user friendly.” - Immunization Clinic nurse&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/reqcheck-patient.png&quot; alt=&quot;ReqCheck’s patient record screen.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;records&quot;&gt;Records&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/reqcheck-old-records.png&quot; alt=&quot;The original vaccine record design&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;The vaccine records the Health Department was using required the nurses to do unnecessary math.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app includes vaccines records for each patient. Previously, they were presented in a hard to read format and didn’t include all relevant data. The redesigned vaccine records are quicker and easier to interpret. Nurses can work more efficiently, with fewer errors. Grouping entries logically allows the reader to quickly scan the chart and determine if a patient is up to date. Nurses previously had to count on their fingers to check date and time frames. Now those calculations are displayed right on the record. The less time nurses spend doing math, the more time they have to counsel patients and provide care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/reqcheck-new-records.png&quot; alt=&quot;ReqCheck's edesigned digital records.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immunizations don’t just keep kids healthy. They’re also a requirement for enrolling in school. A printed version can also be shared with parents, schools, and other medical providers. Vaccine records are complex documents, but non-specialists often need to interpret them. The new designs let everyone make sense of the data they need to help keep kids healthy and in school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/reqcheck-new-records-printed.png&quot; alt=&quot;ReqCheck's redesigned printed records.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="CodeforAmerica" /><summary type="html">ReqCheck is a lightweight web app that interprets vaccine records. I completed this project while a Design Fellow at Code for America, a national nonprofit that makes government services simple, effective, and easy to use. The fellowship is a selective program that pairs teams experienced technologists with cities on a year long project. I worked with the Kansas City, MO Health Department, where my team’s mission was to improve access to childhood immunization.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Graphic Design</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/other/2016/10/10/graphic-design.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Graphic Design" /><published>2016-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/other/2016/10/10/graphic-design</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/other/2016/10/10/graphic-design.html">&lt;p&gt;As a freelance graphic designer I have created posters, logos, and invitations for a variety of clients. I work with organizations and individuals to solve visual problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/other-graphic-design.png&quot; alt=&quot;Examples of my graphic design work&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="other" /><summary type="html">As a freelance graphic designer I have created posters, logos, and invitations for a variety of clients. I work with organizations and individuals to solve visual problems.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Form Design</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/10/forms.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Form Design" /><published>2016-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/10/forms</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/10/forms.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/forms-paperwork.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nurse with piles of paperwork&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;form-redesign&quot;&gt;Form Redesign&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forms are a major point of interaction between clients and the Kansas City, MO Health Department. A redesign of the clinic’s intake paperwork represented a huge opportunity to save time, reduce errors, and improve service delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with an audit of the current paperwork. The system in place involved forms created by different entities, leading to a fragmented experience. I found lots of repetition. Patients were being asked the same questions over and over again. There was also conflicting information, and a different visual style from form to form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/forms-question-audit.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;I collected the intake forms and tallied how many times each question was asked.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used this data, as well as information gathered through observing and interviewing staff and clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I completed a total redesign of the four main intake forms, as well as creating a new form for the &lt;a href=&quot;/codeforamerica/2016/10/10/client-outreach.html&quot;&gt;text message outreach program&lt;/a&gt;. The new forms feature condensed questions and simplified language. I also created a consistent, easy to read visual design system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/forms-paper-forms.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Designs for paper forms&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/forms-online-forms.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Mockups for online intake forms&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;forms-forever&quot;&gt;Forms forever&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project kicked off an &lt;a href=&quot;/codeforamerica/2016/10/09/DesignEducations.html&quot;&gt;enduring interest&lt;/a&gt; in form design. At its root, the purpose of design is to help people understand information. I usually approach this from a visual or interactive standpoint, but language is also a huge component. I love to transform complex ideas and bureaucratic language into simple, natural writing. Pairing this with beautiful, easy to use inputs can make a huge difference in how people interact with institutions. Forms!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="CodeforAmerica" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Content Management Tools</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/other/2016/10/10/content-managment-tools.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Content Management Tools" /><published>2016-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/other/2016/10/10/content-managment-tools</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/other/2016/10/10/content-managment-tools.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;content-tracking-tool&quot;&gt;Content Tracking Tool&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explorations for a complex, information dense interface. View an &lt;a href=&quot;http://racheledelman.github.io/buzzfeed-demos/demo-01/&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/a&gt; prototype I built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/other-cms-tracker.png&quot; alt=&quot;Iterations on article metadata interface&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;moderation-interface&quot;&gt;Moderation Interface&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design for an interface where moderators can view, edit, and promote user submitted content. Through observing moderators work with the previous version of this tool, I was able to identify inefficient and confusing patterns and introduce solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/other-cms-moderation1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Moderation interface&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My process includes observation, documentation, iteration, and usability testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/other-cms-moderation2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Process&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="other" /><summary type="html">Content Tracking Tool</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Text Message Outreach</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/10/client-outreach.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Text Message Outreach" /><published>2016-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/10/client-outreach</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/10/client-outreach.html">&lt;p&gt;I wrote and tested content for a text message outreach campaign for the Kansas City, MO Health Department during my Code for America fellowship. I also created resources to train staff to run it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;outreach-program&quot;&gt;Outreach program&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/outreach-sms-usability.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Paper prototypes for content testing with users.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For busy parents who don’t have a primary care provider, keeping on top of immunizations can be hard. We wanted to meet people where they were, using technology they were comfortable with. We decided to implement an outreach campaign to send text message reminders and alerts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First came research. I intercepted parents in the health department lobby and at a nearby preschool. I interviewed them about their routines, their relationship with the health department, and their usage of text messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used that research to write a variety of text messages. The challenge was to craft clear, HIPAA compliant messages that fit the size constraints of a text message. I then tested the message content with parents to make sure the content made sense to recipients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the text messages I wrote, we ran a number of pilot programs. We sent over 10,000 text messages. The promising results convinced us that the Health Department should be sending regular vaccine reminders by text message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“[The messages] remind me to go early rather than leaving it to the last minute like I did last year.” - A KCHD client&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;staff-training&quot;&gt;Staff training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conduct our text message campaigns, we used two off the shelf products, Twilio and TextIt. Because the Health Department has limited technical resources, it was important to ensure a non-technical person could take over the outreach program. To that end, we decided to document the entire process. We also wanted to create a resource that would be helpful to wider public health community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put together a website, and with my team, wrote an extensive tutorial. The website includes instructions on implementation, as well as advice on best practices. We hope it will be a resource not only for the Kansas City Health Department, but also other public health organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/outreach-sms-tutorial.png&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage of Text Messaging for Public Health tutorial&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="CodeforAmerica" /><summary type="html">I wrote and tested content for a text message outreach campaign for the Kansas City, MO Health Department during my Code for America fellowship. I also created resources to train staff to run it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Careers Site</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/other/2016/10/10/careers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Careers Site" /><published>2016-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/other/2016/10/10/careers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/other/2016/10/10/careers.html">&lt;p&gt;Design for a careers microsite. This site has two distinct goals. I needed to list content, but also sell it to visitors. The visual design gives the impression of an energetic, modern, and global business. I filled it with bright graphics keep the page from being too text heavy. Job listings are interspersed with information about benefits and company vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A large number of listings targeting a wide variety of job seekers necessitated multiple forms of navigation. I gave users the option to filter by department or location, or simply scan all the openings. This meets the needs of applicants looking for a specific job, as well as users looking for general information. Featured listings are highlighted, allowing HR to boost the profile of certain opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Profiles of employees bring in a human touch, while showing applicants that upward mobility is possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/other-careers1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Desktop version of careers site&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responsive design reaches the user wherever they are. The site was designed mobile first. These wireframes show how the site responds to different viewports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/other-careers2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Desktop, tablet, and mobile version of site&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="other" /><summary type="html">Design for a careers microsite. This site has two distinct goals. I needed to list content, but also sell it to visitors. The visual design gives the impression of an energetic, modern, and global business. I filled it with bright graphics keep the page from being too text heavy. Job listings are interspersed with information about benefits and company vision.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Syracuse Business Portal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/10/BusinessPortal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Syracuse Business Portal" /><published>2016-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/10/BusinessPortal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/10/BusinessPortal.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/smallbiz-syr-homepage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Business Portal homepage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can the city of Syracuse, New York best serve local business owners? With a small, but dedicated staff, the city’s Division of Business Development needed an online presence to compliment their in-person services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“To grow our economy we don’t have the ability to talk to every single person with an idea. We felt it was important to make that if you have an idea, you have a place to go to start thinking about it.” - &lt;a href=&quot;http://wrvo.org/post/syracuse-web-portal-one-stop-shop-businesses&quot;&gt;Deputy Commissioner of Business Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We built &lt;a href=&quot;https://business.syrgov.net/&quot;&gt;business.syrgov.net&lt;/a&gt;, a portal where local entrepreneurs can learn about starting a business, find city regulations, check the status of their permits, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the product designer on this team, were I worked alongside a service designer, a product manager, and several engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;process&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/smallbiz-tracker-iterations.png&quot; alt=&quot;Variations on search prompt text.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Microcopy iterations. Every detail of the site was designed with care, and I went through multiple iterations of each aspect of the site.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;accessibility&quot;&gt;Accessibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A government website must serve all residents. I needed to meet users where they were, which includes a diverse range of abilities, devices, languages, and levels of digital literacy. I designed the layout mobile-first, so users would have an excellent experience whether they were on their phone or a desktop computer. I chose system fonts so the content would load quickly, even for users on poor connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;visual-design&quot;&gt;Visual Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The visual identity is designed to be to modern and approachable, yet authoritative. Entrepreneurs should feel welcome on the site, and trust it to give them accurate, up to date information on regulations and requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hierarchy-and-navigation&quot;&gt;Hierarchy and Navigation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our research uncovered that one of the biggest barriers facing new business owners is a lack of knowledge of the landscape. Specifically, they “don’t know what they don’t know”. It was important to give users a clear path to navigate the site, whether or not they knew exactly what they were looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/smallbiz-syr-layout-iterations.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Wireframes iterating on the homepage layout.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We built on Code for America’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeforamerica.org/government-partners/long-beach-ca&quot;&gt;2016 Fellowship in Long Beach&lt;/a&gt;, where they piloted the Plan, Open, Grow model. To this I added several forms of navigation, including bread crumbs and a table of contents for each section. This allows experienced users to jump to the exact topic they’re interested in, while also providing a clear path to new users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;human-touch&quot;&gt;Human Touch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/smallbiz-syr-content.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of an interior page&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Screenshot of an interior page.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our research showed that that users highly value the ability to interact directly with city staff. I broke up long blocks of content with easily clickable contact links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;application-tracker&quot;&gt;Application Tracker&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, business owners needed to call the city to find out the status of their business license and  permit applications. Our application tracker pulls in data from the city’s permitting software, giving applicants access to quick, up to date statuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/smallbiz-tracker-mockups.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of different screens in the application tracker&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My challenge was to present data so that users could easily find the information that was relevant to them. For logistical reason, we needed to let users look up applications with tracking number, without logging into an account. The applications contain many steps and sub-steps. A developer looking for information on why an inspection failed has different needs than a business owner who wants to know when their license expires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I broke the data up into logical sections with clear headings and added icons and colors to help users scan and understand the information at a glance. I designed a summary section at the top with the overall application status and time sensitive information. For one step of the application, we were unable to get live data from the city’s permitting system. To help users understand what was happening in this step, I added a plain language explanation of the process. This compromise keeps users from feeling in dark as they wait for the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="CodeforAmerica" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Small Business Resource Matcher</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/smallbiz/2016/10/09/ResourceMatcher.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Small Business Resource Matcher" /><published>2016-10-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/smallbiz/2016/10/09/ResourceMatcher</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/smallbiz/2016/10/09/ResourceMatcher.html"></content><category term="SmallBiz" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Design Education</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/09/DesignEducations.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Design Education" /><published>2016-10-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/09/DesignEducations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/codeforamerica/2016/10/09/DesignEducations.html">&lt;p&gt;I have had an number of exciting opportunities to run workshops, give talks, and develop educational materials. I enjoy introducing people to human centered design and helping them discover their creative potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design-for-non-designers&quot;&gt;Design for Non-Designers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/talks/DesignForNonDesigners.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop is a one hour introduction to design basics, with a focus on user interface design. It covers principles and techniques and includes several hands on activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have run it at the 2016 National Day of Civic Hacking, for the the User Experience graduate students at Missouri Western State University, and for City employees in San Diego.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;form-design-for-government&quot;&gt;Form Design for Government&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/talks/FormDesign.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prepared this talk for Data Academy, Kansas City’s internal data bootcamp for government employees. It was informed by my &lt;a href=&quot;/codeforamerica/2016/10/10/forms.html&quot;&gt;intake form redesign project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Made the concepts easy to understand and provided relevant examples. Created a comfortable and welcoming environment in which to discuss data and related projects.” - Workshop participant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;designing-a-government-system-in-a-day&quot;&gt;Designing a Government System in a Day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/talks/DesignAGovSystem.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with two other Fellows, I ran this breakout session at the 2016 Code for America Summit. We showed how design sprints can be used in civic technology, focusing on strategy, innovation, and prototyping.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="CodeforAmerica" /><summary type="html">I have had an number of exciting opportunities to run workshops, give talks, and develop educational materials. I enjoy introducing people to human centered design and helping them discover their creative potential.</summary></entry></feed>
